<?xml version="1.0"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
    <title>Curtis Blackwell</title>
    <link href="https://curtisblackwell.com/blog" />
    <link type="application/atom+xml" rel="self" href="https://curtisblackwell.com/blog/feed.atom" />
    <updated>2021-12-31T22:30:08+00:00</updated>
    <id>https://curtisblackwell.com/blog/feed.atom</id>
    <author>
        <name>Curtis Blackwell</name>
    </author>
                <entry>
    <id>https://curtisblackwell.com/blog/2021-11-09-my-work-distilled</id>
    <link type="text/html" rel="alternate" href="https://curtisblackwell.com/blog/2021-11-09-my-work-distilled" />
    <title>My Work, Distilled</title>
    <published>2021-12-31T22:30:08+00:00</published>
    <updated>2021-12-31T22:30:08+00:00</updated>
    <author>
        <name>Curtis Blackwell</name>
    </author>
    <summary type="html">I solve puzzles.

That may look like observing people work and translating their frustrations into solvable problems. Or maybe designing a solution for someone else to encode in software. Or even writing the code myself. Sometimes it&#039;s identifying and......</summary>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[
        <p><strong>I solve puzzles.</strong></p>

<p>That may look like observing people work and translating their frustrations into solvable problems. Or maybe designing a solution for someone else to encode in software. Or even writing the code myself. Sometimes it's identifying and removing progress blockers.</p>

<p>Regardless of the task, my work feels like a game when I'm at my best. But it's not just a make-the-numbers-go-up game. I need to know the numbers we track are the right numbers. The right numbers represent both progress and cost to avoid unintentional harm.</p>

<p>I know I've "won a game" when my gut tells me I've distilled a problem to its essence. When the solution is clear and elegant.</p>
    ]]></content>
</entry>
            <entry>
    <id>https://curtisblackwell.com/blog/2021-11-08-old-home-page-content</id>
    <link type="text/html" rel="alternate" href="https://curtisblackwell.com/blog/2021-11-08-old-home-page-content" />
    <title>Old Home Page</title>
    <published>2021-12-31T22:30:08+00:00</published>
    <updated>2021-12-31T22:30:08+00:00</updated>
    <author>
        <name>Curtis Blackwell</name>
    </author>
    <summary type="html">My previous home page content feels a little dated, but I feel bad getting rid of it, so I&#039;m keeping it around in the form of a blog post. Here it is.




    
        My name is Curtis&amp;nbsp;Blackwell.
    



    
        I&#039;m a software engineer and......</summary>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[
        <p>My previous home page content feels a little dated, but I feel bad getting rid of it, so I'm keeping it around in the form of a blog post. Here it is.</p>

<hr />

<header>
    <h1 title="Myyy naaame… is Giovanni. An' I'm here to tell youu… that myyy naaame… is Giovaaanniiiiii.">
        My name is <strong>Curtis&nbsp;Blackwell</strong>.
    </h1>
</header>

<section class="intro">
    <p>
        I'm a software engineer and manager.
        I aim to maintain a sustainable state&nbsp;of:
    </p>

    <ul title="These be my career goals.">
        <li>producing high-quality, life-improving&nbsp;work;</li>
        <li>advancing my knowledge and&nbsp;skills;</li>
        <li>leaving things better than I found them;&nbsp;and</li>
        <li>encouraging others to do the&nbsp;same.</li>
    </ul>
</section>

<hr>

<p>
    I live for work that provides <strong>social benefit</strong> and revolves around
    <strong>refining&nbsp;operations</strong>.
</p>

<p>
    A recent project serves as a perfect example: The <a href="https://laravel.com/">Laravel</a>
    app tracks inventories for a refugee-employing company, helping it operate
    <span title="Yes.">smoothlier</span>.&nbsp;<span class="hashtag" title="#hashtag">#2017&nbsp;#april</span>
</p>

<p>It helps the&nbsp;company:</p>

<ul>
    <li>import product data from a Shopify&nbsp;store,</li>
    <li>
        assign a
        <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Bill_of_materials">bill&nbsp;of&nbsp;materials</a> to
        each product,&nbsp;and
    </li>
    <li>
        create and fulfill
        <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Production_order">production&nbsp;orders</a>.
    </li>
</ul>

<p>
    These features work together to automate changes where possible, like in products' and
    materials' stocks. The app also sends/receives updates to/from Shopify when&nbsp;appropriate.
</p>

<p>
    In the past, I worked on a coworking space's
    <span title="Statamic v1 for the curious">CMS</span>-powered member/admin dashboard. I planned
    and built features&nbsp;to:
</p>

<ul>
    <li>
        manage members' Stripe subscriptions across multiple Stripe accounts
        (one&nbsp;per&nbsp;location),
    </li>
    <li>send all Stripe transactions to multiple Xero accounts (one&nbsp;per&nbsp;location),</li>
    <li>
        allow members to print via Google Cloud Print, charging per-page after using monthly
        credit,&nbsp;and
    </li>
    <li>help staff manage guest tours and send half-canned/half-fresh follow-up&nbsp;emails.</li>
</ul>

<hr>

<p>
    As for JavaScript, HTML, and CSS, there's not much to say beyond, "I'm more than competent." I
    like Vue and&nbsp;Sass. <span title="¯\_(ツ)_/¯">¯\_(ツ)_/¯</span>
</p>

<p>
    In general, I like to try and keep code as DRY as possible (like
    <span title="ㅠㅠ">Thomas Jerome Newton's home-planet dry</span>), without wasting time on
    diminishing&nbsp;returns.
</p>

<p>I have other skills and traits that prove useful all the&nbsp;time:</p>

<ul>
    <li>understanding&nbsp;of&nbsp;design</li>
    <li>ability to provide constructive, actionable&nbsp;criticism</li>
    <li>confidence to speak bluntly with the tact to know when to tread&nbsp;softly</li>
</ul>

<p>…and some less&nbsp;often:</p>

<ul>
    <li>mid-level Korean&nbsp;proficiency</li>
    <li>expert&nbsp;chopstickery</li>
    <li>
        <span title="Don't act like you're not impressed.">
            ability to open doorknobbed doors with my&nbsp;foot
        </span>
    </li>
</ul>
    ]]></content>
</entry>
            <entry>
    <id>https://curtisblackwell.com/blog/2021-11-04-generating-random-alphanumeric-strings-with-faker</id>
    <link type="text/html" rel="alternate" href="https://curtisblackwell.com/blog/2021-11-04-generating-random-alphanumeric-strings-with-faker" />
    <title>Generating random alphanumeric strings with Faker</title>
    <published>2021-12-31T22:30:08+00:00</published>
    <updated>2021-12-31T22:30:08+00:00</updated>
    <author>
        <name>Curtis Blackwell</name>
    </author>
    <summary type="html">Just wanted to share a quick little thing I learned you could do with Faker, a library I&#039;ve been using for years in writing tests.

Fuck context, show me the coolness.

I&#039;m writing tests for an API integration where I need to fake some IDs that, in......</summary>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[
        <p>Just wanted to share a quick little thing I learned you could do with <a href="https://fakerphp.github.io">Faker</a>, a library I've been using for years in writing tests.</p>

<p><em><a href="#tldr-mofo">Fuck context, show me the coolness.</a></em></p>

<p>I'm writing tests for an API integration where I need to fake some IDs that, in production, would come from the API. The IDs are always 20–24-character alphanumeric strings.</p>

<p>At first, I thought I might need to do something like use the <code>password</code> method and make sure it was long enough that I could strip out any non-alphanumeric characters. But that felt tedious and over-engineered, so I started thinking about shuffling a long alphanumeric string and truncating it.</p>

<p>Then I noticed the <a href="https://fakerphp.github.io/formatters/numbers-and-strings/#regexify"><code>regexify</code> method</a>. It's a little weird to use a searching/matching pattern as a way to generate a random string, but it was simple and intuitive enough.</p>

<pre><code id="tldr-mofo" class="language-php">$this-&gt;faker-&gt;regexify('[a-z0-9]{20,24}');
</code></pre>
    ]]></content>
</entry>
            <entry>
    <id>https://curtisblackwell.com/blog/2021-10-24-gettin-better-without-ron-funches</id>
    <link type="text/html" rel="alternate" href="https://curtisblackwell.com/blog/2021-10-24-gettin-better-without-ron-funches" />
    <title>Gettin&#039; Better without Ron Funches</title>
    <published>2021-12-31T22:30:08+00:00</published>
    <updated>2021-12-31T22:30:08+00:00</updated>
    <author>
        <name>Curtis Blackwell</name>
    </author>
    <summary type="html">A little over 2 months ago, I admitted to myself that I&#039;m burnt out. That I&#039;ve been burnt out for a long time, maybe even several years.

I recently ended a month-long leave of absence to start my recovery process. I started re-learning how to be a......</summary>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[
        <p>A little over 2 months ago, I admitted to myself that I'm burnt out. That I've been burnt out for a long time, maybe even several years.</p>

<p>I recently ended a month-long leave of absence to start my recovery process. I started re-learning how to be a human. Paying more attention to my overwhelmed senses<sup id="fnref:1"><a href="#fn:1" class="footnote-ref" role="doc-noteref">1</a></sup> and the pains in my body.</p>

<p>I've found that stream-of-consciousness journaling helps me to find peace when I'm feeling overwhelmed. And when I go re-read my thoughts, I often find thoughts I benefit from diving deeper into and organizing. I find little nuggets o' wisdom that help me make more intentional/strategic decisions about what I want to do. I'm starting to recognize more personal agency and feel less like life is happening to me.</p>

<p>So, inspired by <a href="Inspiring%20People.md">people I admire and receive "anonymous mentorship" from</a>, I decided to start publishing some of what I'm learning and thinking about. I hope my writing helps others, similar to how theirs helps me.</p>

<p><small markdown="1">
P.S.<br />
I love me some Ron Funches and recently discovered his podcast, <a href="https://ronfunches.com/gettin-better">Gettin' Better with Ron Funches</a>. Just thought it would be a funny name for this. ¯&#92;&#95;(ツ)_/¯
</small></p>

<div class="footnotes" role="doc-endnotes">
<hr />
<ol>

<li id="fn:1" role="doc-endnote">
<p>I'm an <abbr title="highly sensitive person"><a href="https://hsperson.com/">HSP</a></abbr>&#160;<a href="#fnref:1" class="footnote-backref" role="doc-backlink">&#8617;&#xFE0E;</a></p>
</li>

</ol>
</div>
    ]]></content>
</entry>
            <entry>
    <id>https://curtisblackwell.com/blog/2021-10-16-who-or-what-do-my-values-serve</id>
    <link type="text/html" rel="alternate" href="https://curtisblackwell.com/blog/2021-10-16-who-or-what-do-my-values-serve" />
    <title>Who/What do my values serve?</title>
    <published>2021-12-31T22:30:08+00:00</published>
    <updated>2021-12-31T22:30:08+00:00</updated>
    <author>
        <name>Curtis Blackwell</name>
    </author>
    <summary type="html">Who/what do my values serve? ➡️ I want to start considering the impact at scale my values have.

Does my vegetarianism matter, for example?

It complicates my life, but doesn&#039;t really have much of an impact. There aren&#039;t several other people eating......</summary>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[
        <p><img src="/assets/img/evolution-of-values.jpg" alt="Excerpt from my handwritten journal, content below image" /></p>

<p>Who/what do my values serve? ➡️ I want to start considering the <em>impact at scale</em> my values have.</p>

<p>Does my vegetarianism matter, for example?</p>

<p>It <mark class="bg-gradient-to-r from-purple-300 to-purple-50">complicates</mark> my life, but doesn't really have much of an impact. There aren't several other people eating vegetarian because I am. It just makes it harder to find restaurants to eat at with friends or work colleagues. The best I can tell, is that it forces others to see how difficult it can be to find viable vegetarian options.</p>

<aside class="p-4 text-sm bg-gradient-to-r from-purple-300 to-purple-50">

<p>Harder to do things with others. To eat at restaurants. To try things like a keto diet.</p>

</aside>

<p>Similarly(?) I've never pursued wealth, because I don't really value it. But I do value <mark class="bg-gradient-to-r from-rose-300 to-rose-50">freedom</mark>. I think I want to try and get rich so I can feel secure in <mark class="bg-gradient-to-r from-blue-300 to-blue-50">doing what I want when I want</mark>.</p>

<aside class="p-4 text-sm bg-gradient-to-r from-rose-300 to-rose-50">
  <p>Dictating what I spend my time and energy on.</p>
  
  <p>Feeling like I drive my work rather than my work drives me.</p>
  
  <p>Over 50% of my available time is spent working for a <mark class="bg-gradient-to-r from-rose-400">company</mark>, but I don't value the work I'm doing.</p>
  
  <aside class="p-4 text-sm bg-gradient-to-r from-rose-400">
    <p>or resting/commuting/preparing to be able to do the work.</p>
  </aside>
</aside>

<aside class="p-4 text-sm bg-gradient-to-r from-blue-300 to-blue-50">
  <p>Today I looked at the Teenage Engineering website. I want to buy some <mark class="bg-gradient-to-r from-blue-400">Pocket Operators and modular synths</mark> to play with. But I know I wouldn't use them since I rarely have the energy <mark class="bg-gradient-to-r from-emerald-300">when priorities would align</mark>.</p>
  
  <aside class="p-4 text-sm bg-gradient-to-r from-blue-400">
    <p>Or the Mayku Multiplier. This could lead to more fulfilling work and an environment better designed for me. And maybe even creating work for others / helping people escape poverty.</p>
  </aside>
  
  <aside class="p-4 text-sm bg-gradient-to-r from-emerald-300">
    <p>I also have relationships I care about. The time I <em>could</em> spend playing with them is before/after work, but then my energy is low or the environment isn't conducive.</p>
  </aside>
</aside>
    ]]></content>
</entry>
    </feed>
